<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: random thoughts | heelhook]]></title>
  <link href="http://heelhook.github.com/blog/categories/random-thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://heelhook.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T04:29:15-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://heelhook.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pablo Fernandez]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Company Smells]]></title>
    <link href="http://heelhook.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/company-smells/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:36:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://heelhook.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/company-smells</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most developers don't need an explanation of what a "* Smell" refers to, but I'm
assuming that the companies that fit the description of this post won't
(incidentally, those companies probably wouldn't read this blog post either). A
"code smell" is an indication, a symptom, within a codebase, of a problem.</p>

<p>A company smell is an indication of a larger problem in an organization.</p>

<p>When a company uses a service for sourcing developers in today's crazy world
that opens with the following epic line:</p>

<blockquote><h4>What we do...</h4>

<p>We're a new style of recruiting service that charges by the hour
for our time.</p></blockquote>

<p>As a developer/hacker/überninja/engineering-talent all I see is a giant red
flag. These are not recruiters that will try to get to understand the
requirements of the position they are trying to fill, nor will they try to
understand how I, as a human being, can contribute (or detract) in that
position. Quite the opposite, the incentive is in delivering a result quickly.
Any result. Quickly. Time is money. And all ruby on rails ninjas are made equal.</p>

<p>The homepage of "theSourcery" goes on to say:</p>

<blockquote><p>We're re-inventing the way recruiting is done by changing the incentive
structure for recruiters and leveraging data and software while keeping our
work human powered and personal.</p></blockquote>

<p>I'll (fail at trying to) overlook the obvious fact that there is no explanation
of what this likely earth-shattering re-invention of the way recruitment is
conducted in their site, I'll just point out how I must be missing something
huge by the fact that one sentence before that they were mentioning how they are
hunting for developers on an hourly rate and later on go on to say that you are
keeping things personal.</p>

<p>It seems that some companies don't get what being on the receiving end of these
type of recruiters is like. The fact that they are charging by the hour
incentivizes all the wrong aspects of recruitment while completely undermining
the positive (and often under appreciated by developers, specially in the HN
crowd).</p>

<p>The company itself seems mildly interesting (sorry for falling into the <em>prima
donna</em> cliché). I'm a bit surprised that they are replicating a feature
currently existent in iOS's Passbook, yet they don't mention it. If I was
writing the job spec I would include the differentiator factor within the first
paragraph; joining a startup (again, specially on this market) requires not only
a good position with fair compensation, but, at least to me, believing in what
the company's outcome and impact will be is extremely important. A lot of us
work for "free" on things when we believe in them enough.</p>

<p>The fact that this particular company will try to hire from a pool of recruiters
that will end up being incentives to spam that hell out of every email address
they get their hands on, is a very powerful company smell: they don't care about
the practices of people they work with, and they'll likely won't care about the
type of developers they find.</p>

<p>No, I'm not replying to your (absolutely decontextualized) email, Angelina.
Sorry.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The value of idle time]]></title>
    <link href="http://heelhook.github.com/blog/2010/02/23/the-value-of-idle-time/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-23T23:08:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://heelhook.github.com/blog/2010/02/23/the-value-of-idle-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have recently read a quote attributed to Einstein, it reads something along the lines of “the best ideas I have I have them while I shave”. This got me thinking, how much idle time do I have on any given month?</p>

<p>I am an Internet junky, and completely obsessed with efficiency, so I may not be a good statistical sample, but bear with me on this one.</p>

<p>Aftter considering the different idle times we get throughout our daily lives, commuting, personal care time, all meals, I have realized that most of those times I have occupied them (except commute since I work out of my home office) with some supposedly time saving activity, whether it is checking my email, browsing, reading blogs, even when I shower I have managed to be able to do “something”, even if it is just listening to music (come to think about it maybe I could tune some podcasts).</p>

<p>It feels like I’m constantly multitasking, maybe this is a good thing, or maybe not. Even now, I am on my way to a medical check up writing this post on my iPhone.</p>

<p>This forces me to ask myself “What’s the value of idle time?”. For some reason it feels like my ideas begin to flow so much better when I’m not doing something else, when I’m only commuting. It would seem like our information overload and constantly-online capabilities on our smartphones, our inclination to be constatly productive has actually defeated it’s own purpose messing with our creativity.</p>

<p>Listening to other people’s ideas requires not listening to ours, at least for a brief moment. You can use others’ ideas as a trigger for inspiration but at one point the marginal value of listening becomes detrimental to our own creativity and innovation. In the very same way that this happens with consumers indifference curves this can’t be quantifies nor generalized as more people require more listening and some people require less listening.</p>

<p>Ok enough about this, I’m going to continue reading on my kindle now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
